Guide to the William Rogers papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
William Rogers papers
1790-1825
MS 1058
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
(1 box)
The papers consist of correspondence of approximately fifty incoming letters and two written by Rogers in 1790 and 1792. His correspondents are chiefly Baptist ministers of the United States and England, discussing church affairs, theological literature, politics, and emigration from England to the United States. Several anti-slavery societies are also mentioned in the letters.
Rogers, William, 1751-1824
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Wallace Stevens, 1954.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence of approximately fifty incoming letters and two written by Rogers in 1790 and 1792. His correspondents are chiefly Baptist ministers of the United States and England, discussing church affairs, theological literature, politics, and emigration from England to the United States. Several anti-slavery societies are also mentioned in the letters.
Arrangement
The letters in this collection are arranged in chronological order.
Appendix: List of Correspondents
Adams, David 1813 Oct 8
Baldwin, Thomas (1753-1826) 1815 Oct 31
Booth, Abraham 1794 Jun 21, 1797 Apr 29
Botaford, Edmund (1745-1819) 1817 Oct 10
Boyd, E.D 1801 Apr 27
Bruen, Matthias (1793-1829) 1825 Apr 9
Button, William 1794 Mar 31, 1795 Oct 20, 1796 May 3, 1796 Oct 25, 1797 Mar 17, 1797 Aug 12
Carey, William (1761-1834) 1803 Oct 17, 1811 Apr 2
Chamberlain, John (1777-1821) 1803 Mar 19
Davy, Albert 1823 Mar 11
Dore, James (-1825) 1794 Jun 20, 1796 Aug 15
Fisher, Moses (1776-) 1816 Jan 29
Hart, William R 1813 Nov 5, 1816 Jun 13
Holcombe, Henry (1762-1824) 1803 Oct 18, 1812 Mar 10
Jones, Horatio Gates (1777-1853) 1820 Feb 9
Jones, Morgan (d. 1797) 1793 Aug 19
Marshman, Joshua (1768-1837) 1819 Mar 8
Potts, Thomas 1801 Jul 27
Rice, Luther (1783-1836) 1814 Sep 5
Richards, William (1749-1818) 1793 Sep 24, 1794 Mar 14, 1794 Mar 23, 1794 Nov 11, 1795 May 1
Rippon, John (1751-1836) 1792 Dec 5, 1794 Mar 22
Rogers, William (1751-1824) 1790 Jul 22, 1792 Jun 15
Ryland, John (1753-1825) 1806 Jun 21, 1806 Aug 28
Smith, Hezekiah (1737-1805) 1794 Apr 13
Stanford, John (1754-1834) 1794 Mar 2, 1794 Oct 3
Stanford, Thomas M. 1824 Feb 23
Stillman, Samuel (1737-1807) 1795 Mar 18
Thomas, David 1820 May 6
Thomas, Timothy 1793 Aug 23, 1794 Oct 17, 1800 May 31, 1802 Sep 7, 1819 Jun 9
Williams, Elisha Scott 1820 Jan 12
Willson, James Renwick (1780-1853) ca. 1817
Winchester, Elhanan (1751-1797) 1794 Mar 31
Baptists -- Great Britain; Baptists -- United States; Religious thought -- 19th century; Slavery -- United States -- Antislavery movements; Great Britain -- Emigration and immigration; Clergy; Rogers, William, 1751-1824
- Original accession
  - Letters
    - 1790-1793 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1794 Feb-Mar (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1794 Apr-Nov (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1795 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1796 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1797 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1800-1802 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1803-1806 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1811-1814 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1815-1819 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1820-1825 (Box 1, Folder 11)